CHRIS TAYLOR

EMBEDDED SYSTEMS ENGINEER

in linkedin.com/in/theotherchristaylor/

SUMMARY

Experienced electrical and embedded systems engineer with strong leadership, management, and communication skills. Specialization in electronic hardware and software product development. Communicates well in both technical and business settings. Experience with a vast array of embedded technologies and platforms from integrated sensor systems to large-scale interactive designs.

EMPLOYMENT

Hygge Power, Embedded Systems Engineer (Contract), Westminster, CO

June 2019 - Current

- Responsible for the development and testing of embedded power control and network communication systems on Hygge's Orchestrated Power Outlet, the OPO2.
- Developed closed-loop power control systems utilizing the dsPIC33 development platform.
- Developed network and user interface systems utilizing FreeRTOS on the ESP32 platform.
- · Builds systems to ensure critical systems reliability and user safety

Meow Wolf Creative Studios, Tech Project Manager, Sante Fe, NM

Apr. 2018 - May 2019

- Leads tech team in design, production, and integration of large -scale interactive technology, lighting, sound, and infrastructure in exhibitions
- Designs interactive electronics, system and infrastructure power, embedded lighting systems, and decentralized sound elements
- Defines infrastructure power and data systems for large-scale exhibit pieces
- · Drives integration of Technology Team with corporate strategic goals and exhibition timelines
- · Forecasts and manages scope, budget, and timelines for multiple simultaneous projects
- Designs project processes/workflows with other functional departments

SparkFun Electronics, Head of Engineering/PMO, SparkFun Electronics, Longmont, CO

2010 - 2018

- Managed a multidisciplinary 11-person team responsible for the design, sourcing, QA, and development of 400+ SparkFun hardware and software products, released at a rate of one product every 7 days
- Identifies and develops electronics products across entire spectrum of embedded technologies
- Responsible for the recruiting and hiring of the SparkFun Engineering team
- Planned, coordinated, and managed the delivery of all B2C and B2B products
- · Coordinated all product releases with SparkFun Marketing, Production, QC, Tech Support, and Education groups.

SparkFun Electronics, Engineer, Longmont, CO

2006 - 2010

- \bullet Personally developed ~20 products for the maker market utilizing PIC, ARM, and AVR development
- · Responsible for the concept, schematic capture, PCB layout, QC, testing, support and release of SparkFun products
- Created products utilizing multiple technologies such as 9DoF sensors, WiFi, power control, Bluetooth, motion control, LED integration, Lidar, and others
- · Developed, maintained, and promoted the In2 Trinity and Solo, an integrated suite of sensors, GPS, power, and sound elements
- Generated videos, tutorials, and blog posts for education, instruction, and product support

SKILLS

HARDWARE: Schematic Capture, PCB Layout, Troubleshooting, DFM, Electronics Manufacturing, Electronics Supply Chain Management, FCC/UL Integration, Documentation, QC, Digital Circuit Design

SOFTWARE/FIRMWARE: C/C++, AVR, Python, Arduino, Linux, Javascript, Computer Vision, PIC/dsPIC, IoT, ESP32, ARM **PROJECT MANGEMENT:** Kepner-Tregoe Certified, Agile, Waterfall, PMI, Client Communication, Collaborative Products

PERSONNEL MANAGEMENT: Hiring, Performance Evaluation, Communication, Organizational Leadership

PORTFOLIO MANAGEMENT: Product Management, Business Analysis, Strategic Integration

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Boulder

2003 - 2007

B.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering 2007
Focus on Computer Science and Embedded Systems

ORGANIZATIONS

Solid State Depot Hackerspace, Boulder CO, Founder

2010 - 2013

2015 - Current

 ${\bf Open\ Source\ Hardware\ Association},\ {\it Member}$